could you explain the difference between
the insurance policy that a commercial
tenant should have and one that
commercial landlord would have and then
maybe I can explain who's paying for
what sure
so a I'll start with the landlord so the
landlord's responsible for the building
and the common elements in the building
so if I was doing a if I was doing a
somebody came to me with their with
their building there they're gonna rent
release I would value the building so
again if there was a fire in the
building and the building had to be
replaced there the owner of the building
here's how much it's gonna cost to
replace it and I would look at what
rental income they're generating from it
so that if there's the building's gonna
be out of commission for a period of
time that when they look at all the the
lease or rental income that they're
generating here's what it is so they
have coverage for that plus any contents
that are theirs that they provide so any
any kind of content coverage any kind of
I wouldn't say necessarily I would say
leasehold improvements anything that
they own would take away that is a that
is a removable thing that would be a
property coverage versus a building
coverage and then all the all the things
like the sewer backup water all those
kind of things so if any of those issues
come up they would be covered for that
if I was doing the tenant side what I be
asking for is what I typically see in
the leases is the tenants are being
asked to cover their contents so their
business contents if it's a you know but
the business where they have stock and
inventory and all that kind of stuff all
those kind of things any of the
furniture any of the leasehold
improvements that are made into the
space would be there that would be on
for them to pick up and then the
liability that happens in their space so
if I'm in the you know if I'm in their
office or I'm in there in space and
there's something happens to me I slip
and fall I'm gonna sue them I probably
will sue the building too but I will sue
them and typically what I would see is
the landlord asking the tenant to add
them on as
additional insured party to their policy
so that again if I slipped in their
space and I went to a personal injury
learn he said will sue the tenant into
the building owner that the tenant
policy would pick that up on the behalf
of the of the building owner is a little
confusing for some people the tenant is
paying for their our insurance so it is
described it but the landlord is
actually charging the tenant back for
the insurance that they're getting for
the building so the tenant and sometimes
newer or first-time commercial tenants
will go I can't be right why am I paying
for two insurances well I'm sorry to
tell you that that is the standard at
least in Ontario is that commercial
tenants 95% of commercial tenants pay
for the property owners property taxes
their maintenance on the property and
insurance